# **Jeet Patel**

### Software Developer

With over 3+ years of experience & performance-focused and highly analytical professional, equipped with hands-on experience within the field of computer science, encompassing software developing, as well as mobile, web and desktop application development to support business development initiatives.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Android Developer**

July 2022 – Present

## Whitecap Canada

- Enhanced user experience by implementing efficient threading mechanisms, resulting in a 40% reduction in app lag and a 30% decrease in loading times for resource-intensive operations
- Integrated third-party APIs to extend application functionality and improve user engagement.
- Implemented automated testing processes that reduced bug-related delays by 30%.
- Used OkHTTP, Retrofit2, and GSON to make REST calls and parse json from APIs.
- Built Android native UI using Jetpack Compose and received asynchronous data stream from the feature module through Kotlin Coroutines Flows and View Model to achieve live updates of views.
- Leveraged Kotlin Multi-Platform to consume shared APIs across Android and iOS, achieving a 30% reduction in API integration time and streamlining cross-platform updates.

## **Android Developer**

July 2019 – April 2021

## QBurst

- Developed and launched an Android application that achieved a 4 star rating on the Google Play Store with over 500,000 downloads.
- Integrated third-party payment gateways into mobile applications, resulting in a 40% increase in the number of successful transactions.
- Worked on the on the application side of a network communication scheme required by a new API version on the RESTfulserver.
- Project management was through JIRA, assigned user-stories/bugs to other Developers.
- Utilized GraphQL's data-efficient querying to reduce data consumption by 25%, positively impacting user perception of the app's responsiveness and data usage.
- Developed batch deletion of video clips on Kotlin Multiplatform that provided a shared codebase for core logic elements of features across the Android apps.
- Designed and implemented 20+ unit tests in Kotlin using the JUnit framework for 5+ components to ensure the dataflows of each component meet its design and behave.
- Optimized the page loading algorithm of the magazine content that reduces the loading time to less than 1 sec by giving download priority to the most recently displayed pages.

#### CONTACT

- Brampton, ON (Open to Remote)
- · +1 8073584234
- · developerjeet5699@gmail.com
- <a href="linkedin.com/in/jeet-patel/">linkedin.com/in/jeet-patel/</a>
- https://pats5699.github.io/devportfolio/
- https://github.com/pats569/

#### **SKILLS**

#### Methodologies/Languages:

- · SDLC, Agile/Scrum
- · Java, Kotlin, SQL
- · Android Studio

#### Techniques:

- REST API, XML Parser, JSON Parser, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, XML, Postman, Jest
- SQLite, Shared Preferences, MS SQL Server, AWS EC2

#### Tools and Frameworks:

- MVVM, MVP, Retrofit, Picasso, GSON, Google Volley, Jetpack Compose, KMM
- · Android SDK, NDK, Groovy, Gradle
- · Git, GitHub, Bitbucket
- · MacOS, Linux, Windows

#### **EDUCATION**

Lakehead University Masters of Science Computer Science May 2021 - Dec 2022

Charotar University of Science and Technology

Information Technology

Aug 2016 - Jul 2020

## **Project Experience**

Backup App (500K+ Downloads): | Kotlin, SQLite, Coroutine, Exoplayer, Coil, Jetpack Compose.

Created an easy-to-use "WhatsApp Chat Backup" app for saving chats with a convenient search feature.

Designed the app to securely store text, audio, video, and document files from WhatsApp conversations. Developed a user-friendly interface for managing and recovering chats, ensuring a safe and organized digital communication experience.

Link- https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.softnoesis.backupwhatsapp

**School App:** | Java, Jetpack Compose, Retrofit, Glide, Socket.io, Junit, Espresso, Mockito, Dagger, Lottie, Room, Stripe, Firebase Crashlytics Developed a school management Android app with features like dynamic time-table, study material access, live chat, online tests, assignments, fee management, announcements, and smart attendance.

Link- https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=co.nick.gzoid

**Jetpack Reel:** | Kotlin, Jetpack Compose, MVVM with Clean Architecture, Retrofit, Exoplayer Developed Jetpack Reels, an Instagram Reels clone using Jetpack Compose, offering smooth video playback, and interactive UI. Link- https://github.com/pats5699/JetpackReelClone

**All about UI:** | Java, Kotlin, Jetpack Compose, Jetpack Navigation Component, Jetpack Data Binding, Hilt, Retrofit, Room, Jenkins Explore captivating UIs, interactive animations, and innovative gestures in the Showcase app. Witness stunning design themes, custom components, and performance-optimized animations to inspire modern mobile app development. Link- https://github.com/pats5699/UIDesignsModule

**T5 MCQ Generation for Questions:** | NLP (Natural Language Processing), T5 Transformer, Python, Hugging Face, Textstat The "t5-mcq-generation" project involves generating multiple-choice questions (MCQs) using the T5 Transformer model. The project also encompasses the use of a BERT trained model for generating options (distractors) for these questions. Link- <a href="https://github.com/pats5699/t5-mcq-generation">https://github.com/pats5699/t5-mcq-generation</a>